THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最强肉盾的迷宫攻略～拥有稀少技能体力9999的肉盾，被勇者队伍辞退了～》
My name is Greed.
我的名字叫葛利德
But
不过
it seems you already know who I am.
你们看起来好像早就认识我了呢
Greed,
葛利德
shut down the labyrinth immediately and surrender.
马上给我关闭迷宫 并且乖乖投降
If you do, I'll spare you.
这样我就饶你一条小命
Oh, my… And why should I?
哎呀…我为什么要听你的话？
We've wiped out all the monsters
你派到镇上的魔物
you sent to the town.
全都被我们消灭了
You should be aware of our strength.
你也看到我们的战力了吧
Is that so?
是这样吗
He sent out that many monsters again!
居然又派了那么多魔物…
Rud, calm down!
路德 你冷静点
That's right. I can't let him get to me.
没错 我要冷静一点
It's regrettable.
很遗憾
Merely relying on the monsters you've dispatched
光靠你派出去的那些战力 是不可能击溃阿凡锡亚的
Is that really the case?
真的是这样吗
I can continuously summon monsters with nearly unlimited points, you know?
我可是能用近乎无限的点数 不断召唤魔物哦？
It's only a matter of time before the town perishes.
击溃那里只是时间问题罢了
Before that, we'll defeat you and destroy this labyrinth.
在那之前我们会先把你打倒 并且破坏掉这个迷宫
On another note,
话说回来
there's something I've been curious about.
有件事让我一直很在意
Those two over there
那边那两个人
are Homunculi, right?
是人造人吧？
Miss Luna is also a Homunculus?
露娜小姐也是人造人？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
Yes.
没错
And?
但是那又如何？
Nothing.
没什么
I'm just a little moved, that's all.
我只是有点感动罢了
After all, in my past research,
毕竟在我过去的研究中 从没看过像你这样…
I've never seen Homunculi grow as remarkably as you!
成长得这么出色的人造人
I never expected that living outside could have such an impact on Homunculi!
没想到在外面生活 居然能带给人造人这种影响
How about it?
怎么样？
Won't you come back to me?
想不想回到我身边啊？
Sir Rud is my one and only
我的主人
master!
只有路德大人一个人
Luna. Rud.
露娜 路德
Why didn't you tell us?
你们为什么瞒着我们？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm really sorry that I kept it from you guys all this time…
至今以来一直瞒着你们 真的很抱…
Good grief.
真是的
You better explain yourself when we get back,
之后要好好跟我们说明哦
Luna!
露娜
Yes!
好的
My, my…
真是的
In that case…
那么
I might as well take everything by force.
我干脆把这一切都夺过来好了
Although I'm not quite fond of this form of mine very much.
虽然我不是很喜欢这副模样的自己
Such a heavy attack!
好沉重的攻击
But as long as I reinforce my whole body with mana…
不过 只要用魔力强化全身的话…
Saminina, dodge!
萨米弥娜 快躲开
Are you all right?
你还好吗
I'm fine.
还好
More importantly,
话说回来
did you block that damage with your shield force?
你刚才是帮我挡下了护盾的损伤吗
Yes.
没错
You don't have to do that.
你不必这么做
My life is meant
我这条命 是用来拯救所有人造人的
You can use me as a disposable weapon!
你可以把我当作 用完就丢的武器使用
So whether you live or die doesn't matter as long as we defeat Greed?
所以只要能打倒葛利德 你是生是死都没差吗
Yes.
是的
Then
那么
you're not allowed to participate in this battle.
你不准参加这场战斗
Because I don't want anyone to sacrifice themselves.
因为我不希望有人因此牺牲
I am a Homunculus.
我是人造人
I don't have a life to begin with.
本来就没有生命
Greed only sees you as tools to use.
葛利德只把你们当道具使用
Are you trying to make me treat you
你这样是想让我
like the humans you despise?
像你们最讨厌的人类那样对待你吗
If not,
不是的话
then don't sacrifice yourself in battle,
就不要为了战斗 牺牲自己的性命
do you understand?
知道吗
Really.
真是的
I'm surprised you guys still have the leisure to chat.
你们还有闲情逸致在这里聊天啊
"Magic Shield"!
"魔法保护罩"
You've got quite a few tricks up your sleeves.
小伎俩还挺多的嘛
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
Is that a skill?
这是技能吗
How annoying.
真讨人厌啊
What?
什么
I nullified your magic.
我把你的魔法无效化了
How dare you!
好大的胆子
You rascals! How dare you do this to me!
混账 你们竟敢这样对我
Let… Let go of me! Let go of me!
放…放开我 快放开我
My power is being…
力量被…
Could it be that these cuffs are…
难道这个手铐是…
Curses!
可恶
Take this!
看招
"Life Burst"!
"生命爆发"
Sir Hero…
勇者大人
Don't let your guard down!
别松懈
Y… Yes!
好…好的
You guys did well.
你们…真的很厉害
So have some confidence in yourselves!
所以给我有自信一点
Yes.
是
Amazing!
好厉害
Miss Amon, please join the battle as well.
亚蒙小姐 请你也一起来战斗吧
But I'm tired.
但我已经累了
I do not fancy a man that is annoying.
人家可不喜欢太烦人的家伙
Lady Manicia
玛妮西娅大人说
prepared these super sweet doughnuts for the hardworking Miss Amon.
这个超甜的甜甜圈是要做给 努力战斗的亚蒙小姐的
Shall I tell her not to bother preparing them
要我跟她说你没在战斗
since you are not participating in the battle?
所以不用准备甜甜圈了吗
W… What?
什…什么？
Why didn't you say so earlier?
你…你倒是早点说啊
I never said I wasn't going to fight!
我可没说自己不战斗哦
My woeful kin,
可怜的眷属们啊
return to the darkness!
回归黑暗吧
"Chat Magic Balnoir"!
"Chat Magic Balnoir"
Run!
快逃
Please don't destroy the town.
拜托你们不要连城镇都一并毁掉啊
Well then, let's take Greed back to the town with us.
那么 我们也带着葛利德回镇上吧
What's this?
这是…
Do Demon Lords have this kind of magic stone in their chests?
魔王的胸口有这种魔石吗
No, could it be…
不对 难道说…
What's going on?
怎么回事？
This magic…
这股魔力…
It's nothing like we've ever been up against.
强到无法和过去的对手相提并论
Are you the real one?
你就是本尊吗
I created him based on my memories and abilities,
他是我按照自己的记忆和能力 做出来的
so I'd say that Homunculus is as good as the real one.
所以那个人造人姑且也算本尊哦
Though its combat abilities leave much to be desired.
不过战斗力好像做得太弱了
My name is Greed.
我的名字叫葛利德
A pleasure to make…
初次见面…
I believe we can skip the formalities.
这种客套话应该就免了吧
We'll soon bid each other farewell anyway.
反正我们很快就要说再见了
If it's this attack speed…
如果是这个攻击速度…
Rud!
路德
I'm fine!
我没事
With a lift of his finger,
他只是轻轻动一下
he can conjure up such a powerful attack!
竟然就能使出这么强的威力吗
I must use my mana to make myself stronger, or I won't be able to defeat him.
必须用魔力让自己变得更厉害 否则无法打败他
Rud!
路德
Seems we can't use the move we used against Amon to deal with him.
看来没办法用攻击亚蒙的那招 对付他呢
Skill: "Fusion"!
技能"融合"
Don't worry.
别担心 就这样继续攻击
Prepare yourself!
觉悟吧
Miss Saminina!
萨米弥娜小姐
Thank you!
谢谢你
Everyone, regroup.
所有人 重整态势
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Master!
主人
That took a great deal off my shield force.
护盾…被消耗掉了很多
I'll distract him.
我来引开他的注意
Please restore Rud's shield force.
麻烦你去帮路德回复护盾
Got it.
好
Even as Lilialy,
即便是在莉莉亚莉状态下
they can only defend against Greed.
对上葛利德 也只能一个劲地防守吗
We'll have to seize the opportunity
看来只能抓准时机
and take him down with one powerful strike.
用强力的攻击一招干掉他了
Otherwise, we won't stand a chance.
不然感觉没有胜算
"Taunt"!
"挑衅"
It's futile.
没用的
I've accumulated 20,000 damage so far.
目前累积的伤害是2万点
Let's settle this with this move!
就用这招一决胜负
"Life Conversion"!
"生命转换"
Luna! Saminina!
露娜 萨米弥娜
Get them to Nin!
把她们带去妮恩那边
Got it.
是
No way!
不会吧
Lilia and Lily are incapacitated.
我们这边的莉莉亚和莉莉 都无法战斗了
What should we do?
该怎么办才好
Even with my current mana enhancement,
现在的魔力强化程度
I stand no chance against him in speed and strength.
在力量和速度方面都没有胜算
More…
要将更多…
I need to channel more mana into my body!
将更多的魔力注入全身
Dang it!
可恶
That one hit depleted all of my shield force!
一击就把我的护盾耗尽了
But this means
但是
I can use "Life Conversion" one more time.
这样就能再用一次"生命转换"了
Let the mana flow throughout my body.
让魔力在全身流动
This time, I have to finish him with everything I've got!
这次一定要用尽所有力量干掉他
"Life Conversion"!
"生命转换"
Rud!
路德
Did my shield shatter?
护盾…碎了吗
Even with the mana enhancement,
就算注入魔力
it hurts so much I can't move.
也痛到无法动弹
Everyone, run!
各位 快逃
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Miss Luna! Miss Nin! Get behind me!
露娜小姐 妮恩小姐 快躲到我身后
-Was I knocked away by Greed's attack? -Luna, get over here!
-我被葛利德的攻击打飞了吗 -露娜也快点过来
Saminina!
萨米弥娜
-I have to hurry… -Dang it!
-得快点… -可恶
I have to save everyone!
得快点去救大家才行
Dang… Dang it!
可…可恶
I can't muster up my mana…
没办法顺利…使出魔力
Come on!
快点
Everyone's shield force…
大家的护盾…
is depleted!
都耗尽了
Luna!
露娜
At this rate,
这样下去露娜…
Luna and everyone will...
以及大家都会…
Get up!
快动起来啊
Please!
拜托了
Curses!
可恶
Let all my mana
让所有魔力
flow through my body.
全部流入身体里
Ignore the pain.
别管身上那些疼痛了
Break the limits!
突破自己的极限吧
I am...
因为我是…
the tank of this party!
这个小队的肉盾
Rud?
路德？
R… Rud?
路…路德？
Destroy!
破坏掉吧
-There's a voice echoing in my head. -Destroy!
-脑中一直有个声音 -破坏掉吧
Destroy!
破坏掉吧
-It wants me to destroy everything. -Destroy…
-要我把一切破坏殆尽 -破坏掉吧…
Channel more mana into my body.
让更多魔力在全身流动
Keep hitting until this guy breaks!
要一直打到这家伙不能再战斗为止
Over and over!
一直打
This is... so satisfying!
真是…太开心了
Rud!
路德
Who is it?
是谁？
I can't see them.
看不太清楚
Is there someone else here?
还有其他人在这里吗
Then,
那么
I must destroy them too.
得一并破坏掉才行
Come to your senses!
快清醒过来
Nin?
妮恩？
I put some magic in that slap.
我稍微用魔法打了你
Well? Are you back to normal?
怎么样？清醒过来了吗
Uh… yeah.
呃…嗯
I was consumed by my mana.
我刚才好像被魔力吞噬了
Is that why I lost control?
所以才会丧失自我吗
Rud!
路德
My mana is acting up again…
魔力又擅自…
Destroy...
-破坏掉吧… -你要学会控制
Those who cannot control their mana
没办法控制魔力的人
will become monsters.
就会变成魔物
That voice...
那个声音
I've heard that voice somewhere before.
我之前好像也在哪里听到过
That's…
原来那是…
my voice.
我的声音
If this continues,
再这样下去 我可能会变成魔物 最终失控暴走
Rud!
路德
Deep breaths.
先深呼吸
I need to control my mana.
必须控制住魔力才行
Rud!
路德
Thank you, Nin.
妮恩 谢谢你
Thanks to you,
多亏有你 我才能顺利控制住魔力
Thank goodness.
太好了
Now's not the time to let myself be overwhelmed by my mana.
现在可不是被魔力吞噬的时候
I have to protect everyone.
我必须…保护大家
Greed!
葛利德
The town you wish to protect is no more!
你要守护的地方已经完蛋了
I'll make sure they,
我要让他们
along with your party,
和你们一起
are completely eradicated
一个不留地
from this world!
从这个世上排除
Nin, I need your help.
妮恩 我想请你帮个忙
Keep casting healing magic on me.
接下来不断对我施展回复魔法
Don't stop for even a second.
一刻都不能停下
I want to bet everything
我想将一切
on this strike.
全都赌在这一击上
I know this request is reckless...
我知道这个请求很乱来…
What are you saying at a time like this?
事到如今 你还在说什么啊
I'm the healer of this party.
我可是这个小队的补师哦
Go ahead and do what you need to do!
放手去做吧
Will do.
好
Just hold on a little longer, everyone! Don't give up!
再撑一下就好 大家别放弃
Life Burst!
生命爆发
You're a hundred years too early to lay a hand on me!
想碰到我 你还早了一百年呢
Here's a newly made sword.
这边有一把新做好的剑
Take it!
快点拿去
Please heal the ones over there first
请让那边的人优先治疗
and get more bandages.
并且多拿一些绷带过来
Greed,
葛利德
we owe all of this to you.
这都是多亏了你哦
Adventurers,
冒险者
Vigilante Corps,
自警团
Homunculi,
人造人们
Marius,
玛里乌斯
Amon,
亚蒙
as long as I'm in the same space with everyone,
只要跟大家待在同个空间
my skills can link them.
我的技能就能辨识到他们
"Sacrificial Shield"!
"牺牲之盾"
My body suddenly became lighter.
身体好像突然变轻了耶
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
The shield force isn't decreasing anymore.
护盾不会减少了
Is this…
这该不会是…
Rud's skill?
路德的技能？
Greed.
葛利德
Thanks to you showing me the vision of Avancier,
多亏你让我看到阿凡锡亚的景象
I was able to transfer all the shield force damage from everyone
我才能把这个空间里的 所有人的护盾损伤
in this space onto myself.
全部转移到自己身上
As the strongest tank,
身为最强肉盾的我
I will protect…
一定会守护住…
everyone!
这一切的
"Life Conversion"!
"生命转换"
Big Brother?
哥哥？
Is that Rud?
是路德吗
Have they returned?
他们回来了吗
It's Rud!
是路德
Rud!
路德
Big Brother!
哥哥
Manicia!
玛妮西娅
Everyone!
各位
Big Brother!
哥哥
I always believed
我一直相信…
you would come back!
你绝对会回来的
I've always come back, haven't I?
我不是每次都有回来吗
That's true.
说得也是呢
Welcome back, Big Brother!
欢迎回来 哥哥
I'm back, Manicia.
我回来了 玛妮西娅
Rud!
路德
Marius. Amon.
玛里乌斯 亚蒙
Is everyone all right?
你们没事吧
There were just too many of them.
因为数量实在太多了
I couldn't hold all of them back like you did.
我没办法像你那样 顾到所有地方
But we managed to hold the fort.
但还是勉强把城镇守住了
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Rud!
路德
You actually conquered the labyrinth in such a short time!
你真的在这么短的时间内 成功攻略迷宫了
Incredible!
太强了
Everyone…
各位…
It's thanks to all of you for helping protect Avancier,
多亏有你们帮忙守护阿凡锡亚
that we were able to successfully destroy the labyrinth.
我们才能成功破坏迷宫
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家
Mister Rud?
路德先生
Rud really is
路德果然…
the strongest tank!
是最强的肉盾
I am Rud. I am a tank.
我 路德 是一位肉盾
This is the story of how I, a tank,
这是一部讲述身为队伍盾职的我
became a hero.
摇身一变成为主角
I will continue to work hard
今后也会守护着大家
and protect everyone.
努力奋斗的故事